<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tom Mault</title>
    <description>Graduate Consultant</description>
    <link>http://tmault.co.uk</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tmault.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning How to Learn</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of weekends I have sunk a couple of hours into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/learning-how-to-learn&quot;&gt;studying a MOOC on Coursera called Learning How to Learn&lt;/a&gt;.
Here are a few of the things I learned. Rather than reproduce an exacting list, I’ve explored a few of the bigger themes that have stuck with me a week or two later.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/2015/Learning-How-To-Learn/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/2015/Learning-How-To-Learn/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rosenberg on Reputation</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The sum of it is that no dealer, curator, buyer, or critic, or any existing combination of these, can be depended on to produce a reputation that is more than a momentary flurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/2015/rosenberg/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/2015/rosenberg/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How The Economic Machine Works</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In this video, Ray Dalio lays out a simple framework for thinking about the economy. In his eyes, it is prudent to overlay the short-term debt cycle on the long-term debt cycle. Once you’ve done this, take the two cycles and place them on the (generally less volatile) productivity growth line.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/2015/How-The-Economic-Machine-Works/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/2015/How-The-Economic-Machine-Works/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Links (July 2015)</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Tony Fadell (Ex-Apple, Nest Co-Founder) proposes we think in terms of the thoughtful home, not the internet of things. This extends to ideas like the thoughtful car (TESLA) and the thoughtful city. Technological innovation is meant to offer &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2015/07/the-technology-ratchet.html&quot;&gt;useful improvement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/2015/Links-July-2015/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/2015/Links-July-2015/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>iCloud Photos Needs A Local Storage Limit</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I like iCloud Photos and pay for extra storage.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/2015/iCloud-Photos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/2015/iCloud-Photos/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smart Things</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of things I wished someone had told me earlier in life. I’ve listed a few of them below.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/2015/Smart-Things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/2015/Smart-Things/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CRM Notes</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-crm&quot;&gt;What is CRM?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration of technology and business processes, used in a manner that satisfies the customer in any given interaction. CRM is about acquiring, analysing and using knowledge about customers in order to sell more goods or services and to do so more efficiently. In the long term, a process of continual analysis and refinement of the firms product mix will enhance the lifetime value of the firm to the customer. CRM may involve fundamental process changes within the organisation; simply providing technology is usually inadequate (Page 93).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tmault.co.uk/2014/CRM-Notes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tmault.co.uk/2014/CRM-Notes/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>